<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Thoughts on Credit Risk</title>
    <link>https://example.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Thoughts on Credit Risk</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.151.0</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 14:19:27 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://example.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Credit Expansion</title>
      <link>https://example.com/posts/credit-expansion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 14:19:27 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/posts/credit-expansion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Credit expansion is one of the most exciting yet daunting responsibilities for a credit risk manager. It represents an uncharted landscape filled with opportunities and uncertainty. The scope is broad, covering new market entry, new product launches, and expansion into new customer populations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From my experience in new product and population expansion, such initiatives require a highly cautious and data-driven approach. In new population expansion, which often targets higher-risk borrowers with limited credit history, lenders can either start small with sufficient financial reserves, or transfer part of the risk externally to gain early learning benefits.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pricing</title>
      <link>https://example.com/posts/pricing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 14:18:49 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/posts/pricing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Pricing is one of the most critical decisions in lending, typically co-owned by the product and risk teams, as it has a direct and significant impact on customer behavior and product usage. We’ve often observed shifts in loan term adoption driven purely by changes in the pricing strategy. Because pricing and risk are inseparable, an effective pricing framework must be built on a comprehensive understanding of risk levels and their inherent uncertainty.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Credit Model</title>
      <link>https://example.com/posts/credit-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 13:26:35 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/posts/credit-model/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;All the credit strategy should be powered by models if sufficient data samples available, as models can capture much higher dimension of data information compared with the ones processed by human brain. Using new account model as an example, higher dimension means higher degree of discrimination detected from data, and model can capture true defaulter with less sacrifice of non-defaulter. Therefore we usually use &lt;em&gt;Gini&lt;/em&gt; to measure overall discrimination power and &lt;em&gt;Capture rate at top X%&lt;/em&gt; to check the potential performance in strategy, the way to use the model to set a cutoff threshold to decline applicants. Once a cutoff has been set, it will be natually bring in two types of errors, type I and type II errors. Type I error (false positive) for credit model is to classify non-defaulters as defaulters and yields decline decision. Type II error (false negative) is to consider defaulters as non-defaulters. The cost of Type I error is lossing a good customer, and cost of Type II error is default risk. Therefore, credit risk management is to design a strategy to manage type II error. However you can consider an extreme case, with a perfect model which can score highest for all the defaulters and we set a threshold perfectly to seperate out all the defaulters from non-defaulters, we will have 0% for both Type I and Type II errors; with imperfect model in reality, type I and type II error trade off with each other based on the cutoff selection, which means we will either sacrifice many good customers for low default risk, or bring in more defaulters for high approval rate. Based on above, we can tell the importance of a powerful model, and importance of cutoff threshold selection on the impact of business growth and credit performance. Therefore, the contribution of a good model to bring in more good customer given the same default risk.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Line Philosophy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/posts/line-philosophy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 08:29:32 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/posts/line-philosophy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Initial Line Decision&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond the approval or decline decision at the application stage, the initial line assignment is another key step lenders must determine. The credit line represents the risk exposure — essentially, how much the lender is comfortable extending based on the borrower’s estimated repayment capacity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Line evaluation depends on two main dimensions: repayment ability and risk level. The first ensures that the offered line is meaningful and appropriate given the borrower’s financial condition, such as income and borrowing needs. Ignoring this dimension can result in lines that are too low or irrelevant, making the product less attractive and reducing customer engagement and portfolio growth.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Credit Risk Management</title>
      <link>https://example.com/posts/credit-risk-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 14:23:34 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/posts/credit-risk-management/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What and Why&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;credit risk managemnet&lt;/em&gt; is very critial for lending industry, as lending business model is to control risk to achieve predictable and profitable return based on pre-set risk appetite. Risk appetite relfects in uncertainty, higher level of uncertainty requires more buffer in margin to cover the risk. Therefore, credit risk manager&amp;rsquo;s role is to align risk appetite with business goal to achieve portfolio growth with calculated risk, and to closely monitor acquisition quality and portfolio performance to ensure well alignment with risk appetite.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://example.com/posts/my-first-article/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/posts/my-first-article/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello, Here is the place for me to share the thoughts around credit risk management based on my professional experience. I would like to use this space to inspire continuous learning and growth, and to truly master the essense of lending risk.  date = &amp;lsquo;2025-10-06T13:58:50-04:00&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello! Welcome to my space, where I share insights and reflections on credit risk management drawn from my professional experience. My goal is to use this platform to inspire continuous learning and deepen the understanding of the true essence of lending risk.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
